Miklos Rozsa Papers
Miklos Rozsa Papers
- Correspondence-subject files, general correspondence
  - Newman, Alfred, composer (Box 28)
  - Nicholson, Waltraud (Val) (Box 28)
  - Nick, Rolf (Box 28)
  - Niggio, Patrick, fan (Box 28)
  - Norddeutscher Rundfunk (Hamburg, Germany) (Box 28)
  - Norenberg, Helmut (Herb), fan (Box 28)
  - Norfolk Symphony Orchestra (Norfolk, VA) (Box 28)
  - "Norman" (Box 28)
  - Novello & Company, Ltd. (London, England) (Box 28)
  - Nürnberger Symphoniker (Nuremberg, Germany) (Box 28)
  - O (Box 29)
  - Occidental Life Insurance Company of California (Los Angeles, CA) (Box 29)
  - Ocnoff, Edward E., copyist (Box 29)
  - Omony, Louisa (Box 29)
  - O'Neill, Dennis, clergyperson (Box 29)
  - [The] Ontario Film Institute (Toronto, Ontario, Canada) (Box 29)
  - Orion Master Recordings Inc. (Malibu, CA) (Box 29)
  - Orlando, Salvatore, fan (Box 29)
  - Ormandy, Eugene, conductor (Box 29)
  - Orquestra Sinfonica de Puerto Rico (San Juan, Puerto Rico) (Box 30)
  - Orrin Kabaker & Company Certified Public Accountants (Beverly Hills, CA) (Box 30)
  - Országh, Tivadar, musician (Box 30)
  - Ortolani, Riz, director (Box 30)
  - Österreichischer Rundfunk (Vienna, Austria) (Box 30)
  - Ott's (Santa Barbara, CA) (Box 30)
  - Outlet Book Company Inc. (New York, NY) (Box 30)
  - Owens, Ruth, musician (Box 30)
  - P (Box 30)
  - Paal, Alexander, producer (Box 30)
  - Pabon Cazzoni, Loris, fan (Box 30)
  - Pacific Lutheran University (Tacoma, WA) (Box 30)
  - Pacific States Loan Company (Los Angeles, CA) (Box 30)
  - Padberg, Rainer, conductor (Box 30)
  - Padin Videla, Jorge Alberto, fan (Box 30)
  - Paine, Webber, Jackson & Curtis (Beverly Hills, CA) (Box 30)
  - Palmer, Christopher, writer (Box 30)
  - Panagopoulos, Paul, fan (Box 31)
  - Pantheon Music International, Inc. (New York, NY) (Box 31)
  - Panuccio, Alessandro (Box 31)
  - Paramount Pictures Inc. (Hollywood, CA) (Box 31)
  - Parcels for the Forces, Inc. (New York, NY) (Box 31)
  - Parkas, Chris, fan (Box 31)
  - Parke-Bernet Galleries Inc, (New York, NY) (Box 31)
  - Parker, Mike, fan (Box 31)
  - Parkin, Eric, musician (Box 31)
  - Parnes, Irwin, publicist (Box 31)
  - Pascal, Gabriel, producer (Box 31)
  - Paul Kohner, Inc. (Hollywood, CA), agent (Box 31)
  - [The] Paul Revere Life Insurance Company (Worcester, MA) (Box 31)
  - Pavelek, James, artist (Box 31)
  - Pearl Photo-Cine (Paris, France) (Box 31)
  - PEMA Music (Paris, France) (Box 31)
  - Pennario, Leonard, musician (Box 31)
  - [The] Performing Right Society Ltd. (London, England) (Box 31)
  - Perkins, Gloria, musician (Box 32)
  - Perry, Alfred (Box 32)
  - Persichetti, Vincent, composer (Box 32)
  - Péteri, Jenöné (Box 32)
  - Petrovits, Eva (Box 32)
  - Petzal, Thomas, see Royal Philharmonic Orchestra (London, England) (Box 32)
  - Peyrot, Yves (Box 32)
  - Phi Beta (Los Angeles, CA) (Box 32)
  - Philbrook Art Center (Tulsa, OK) (Box 32)
  - Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England) (Box 32)
  - [The] Philharmonic Orchestra of Los Angeles (Los Angeles, CA) (Box 32)
  - Phillips Auctioneers (London, England) (Box 32)
  - Phoenix Title & Trust Company (Phoenix, AZ) (Box 32)
  - Photo-Gerber (Nürnberg, Germany) (Box 32)
  - Piatigorsky, Gregor, musician (Box 32)
  - Piattelli, Elio, composer (Box 32)
  - Piccini Brothers Jewellers (Florence, Italy) (Box 32)
  - Piccioni, Piero, composer (Box 32)
  - Piccolo, Nicholas V., fan (Box 32)
  - Pickett, David S., fan (Box 32)
  - Pierangelo, Negri, fan (Box 32)
  - [The] Pittsburgh Symphony Society (Pittsburgh, PA) (Box 32)
  - Pocock & Smith Realtors (Phoenix, AZ) (Box 32)
  - Pocock-Engler & Co. Realtors (Phoenix, AZ) (Box 32)
  - Polgar, Tibor, musician (Box 32)
  - Pollak, Robert, See also Chapman College (Los Angeles, CA); composer (Box 32)
  - Polydor Ltd (London, England), see also Gray, Gordon (Box 32)
  - Pontings (London, England) (Box 32)
  - Ponzio, Enrico, fan (Box 32)
  - Portland Symphony Orchestra (Box 32)
  - Prades, Jaime, producer (Box 32)
  - [The] Presbyterian Hospital (New York, NY) (Box 32)
  - Pressburger, Emeric, writer (Box 32)
  - Previn, André, musician (Box 32)
  - Purdue & Greenhill Estate Agents & Surveyors (London, England) (Box 32)
  - Q (Box 32)
  - Quigley Publications (New York, NY) (Box 32)
  - R (Box 33)
  - Radio-Genève (Geneva, Switzerland) (Box 33)
  - Radio der deutschen und der rätoromanischen Schweiz (Basel, Switzerland) (Box 33)
  - Radio City Music Hall (New York, NY) (Box 33)
  - Radio Corporation of America (Camden, NJ and New York, NY), see also Mohr, Richard (Box 33)
  - Radio Free Europe (London, England), see also Meyer, Nicholas (Box 33)
  - Radio Recorders Inc. (Hollywood, CA) (Box 33)
  - Radio Wien (Vienna, Austria) (Box 33)
  - Radio Zürich (Zürich, Switzerland) (Box 33)
  - Raffee Rug & Carpet Co. (Los Angeles, CA) (Box 33)
  - Rajter, L. (Box 33)
  - Ramanauskas, Stanley, fan (Box 33)
  - Rangel, David, fan (Box 33)
  - Ranki, Gyorgy, composer (Box 33)
  - Raphael, Günter, composer (Box 33)
  - Raksin, David, composer (Box 33)
  - Rattray, Eric and Peggy, producer (Box 33)
  - Rawson, Shirley, fan (Box 33)
  - [The] Raymond H. Miller Organization (Oakland, CA) (Box 33)
  - Reagan, Ronald (Box 33)
  - Reardon, Craig (Box 33)
  - Redwine, H.G. and Olivia M., lawyer (Box 33)
  - Reed, O.P. Jr., gallery (Box 33)
  - Reisch, Walter, writer (Box 33)
  - Renner, Alexander M.D., physician (Box 33)
  - Rennweg & Hammerstein Apotheke & Drogerie (Zurich, Switzerland) (Box 33)
  - Resnais, Alain, director (Box 33)
  - Revai, Andrew (Box 33)
  - RIAS (Berlin, Germany) (Box 33)
  - Riebe, Karl (Box 33)
  - Rijksmuseum (Amsterdam, The Netherlands) (Box 33)
  - Rileigh, Charles, fan (Box 33)
  - Robbins, Danny, musician (Box 33)
  - Robbins Music Corporation (New York, NY) (Box 33)
  - Roche, Corinne (Box 33)
  - Roder, Frank and Launcey (Box 33)
  - [The] Rodgers and Hammerstein Concert Library (New York, NY) (Box 33)
  - Roland-Manuel, Alexis, composer (Box 34)
  - RoLay, T. (Box 34)
  - Rollins Burdick Hunter of Southern California, Inc. (Los Angeles, CA) (Box 34)
  - Romansky, Ljubomir, conductor (Box 34)
  - Rooke, E. Douglas, physician (Box 34)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin and Eleanor (Box 34)
  - Rootes Ltd (London, England) (Box 34)
  - Rose, Augustus, M.D., physician (Box 34)
  - Rosen, Nick (Box 34)
  - Rosenfield, John, journalist (Box 34)
  - Rosenthal, Manuel, conductor (Box 34)
  - Roth, Feri, musician (Box 34)
  - Roth, Lasslo (Box 34)
  - Roy, Christian and Lise (Box 34)
  - Royal Philharmonic Orchestra (London, England) (Box 34)
  - Rózsa, Edith, family (sister) (Box 34)
    See also Jankay, Stephen and Edith.
  - Rózsa, Gyulane (Box 34)
  - Rózsa, Imre and Dinah (Box 34)
  - Rózsa, Juliet, family (daughter) (Box 34)
  - Rózsa, Margaret Finlason (wife)
    - Correspondence, original letters, reproductions from verso of other correspondence (Box 34)
    - Correspondence, 1943-1981; letters from Miklos to his wife, with transcriptions; 8 volumes (Oversize 363-364)
      Gift of Nicholas Rozsa, 2016.
    - Postcards, 1960s-1980s; postcards from Miklos to his wife; 3 volumes (Oversize 353-354)
      Gift of Nicholas Rozsa, 2015.
  - Rózsa, Nicholas (son) (Box 34)
  - Rózsa, Regina Berkovits (mother)
    - Correspondence (Box 34)
    - Postcards, postcards from Miklos, in Hungarian, with English translations (Oversize 355)
      Gift of Nicholas Rozsa, 2013.
  - Rózsa, Sean and Anita (Box 34)
  - Rozsi Mama (Box 34)
  - Rozsnyai, Zoltan, conductor (Box 34)
  - Rubenstein, Arthur, musician (Box 34)
  - Rudolf, E. (Box 34)
  - Rugolo, Pete, composer (Box 34)
  - Rumsey, John and Anne (Box 34)
  - Russ-Bovelino, Wolfgang, musician (Box 34)
  - Russell, Peter J., fan (Box 34)
  - S (Box 35)
  - "S." (Box 35)
  - S_____, Martin, family (Box 35)
  - Società Assicurazioni Rischi Automobilistici (Genova, Italy) (Box 35)
  - Saada, Jacques (Box 35)
  - Sabel, H. (Box 35)
  - Sabu, Jasmine (Box 35)
  - Sacks, Samuel, lawyer; see also Simon & Sheridan (Los Angeles, CA) (Box 35)
  - Sacramento Symphony Association (Sacramento, CA), organization (Box 35)
  - St. Louis String Trio (St. Louis, MO) (Box 35)
  - St. Matthews United Methodist Church (Hacienda Heights, CA) (Box 35)
  - St. Vincent's Hospital (Los Angeles, CA) (Box 35)
  - Salone, Donato (Box 35)
  - Salter, Hans, composer (Box 35)
  - Salzer-Triad Property Management, Inc. (Encino, CA) (Box 35)
  - Sam Fox Publishing Co. (New York, NY) (Box 35)
  - Sample, James, conductor (Box 35)
  - San Gabriel Valley Symphony Association (Arcadia, CA) (Box 35)
  - Sándor, György and Christina, musician (Box 35)
  - Santa Barbara, City of, City Assessor (Box 35)
  - Santa Barbara Museum of Art (Santa Barbara, CA) (Box 35)
  - Santa Monica Symphony Association (Santa Monica, CA) (Box 35)
  - Sattler, Klaus-Peter, composer (Box 35)
  - Savina, Carlo, composer (Box 35)
  - Schary, Dore, producer (Box 35)
  - Scheremetiew, Mikael, conductor (Box 35)
  - Schmidt, Edward, fan (Box 35)
  - Schmidt, Richard, fan (Box 35)
  - Schneer, Charles and Shirley, producer (Box 35)
  - Schneider, Urs, conductor (Box 35)
  - Schoenfeld, Alice and Eleonore, musician (Box 35)
  - Schon, Oswaldo, lawyer (Box 35)
  - Schönzeler, Hans-Hubert, conductor (Box 35)
  - Schulhof, Andrew, manager (Box 35)
  - Schwalb, Miklos, musician (Box 35)
  - Schwartz, Steven, fan (Box 35)
  - Schwartzwald, Milton, producer (Box 35)
  - Schweizerische Bankgesellschaft (Zürich, Switzerland) (Box 35)
  - Schweizerische Rundspruchgesellschaft (Zurich, Switzerland) (Box 35)
  - [The] Scotch House (London, England) (Box 35)
  - Scott, F.M. (Box 35)
  - Scott, Robert John, fan (Box 35)
  - Screen Actors' Guild (Hollywood, CA) (Box 35)
  - Screen Composers' Association (Beverly Hills, CA) (Box 36)
  - Screen Gems-Columbia Music, Inc. (Hollywood, CA) (Box 36)
  - Screen Productions, Inc. (Box 36)
  - Sebestyen, Janos, musician (Box 36)
  - Security-First National Bank of Los Angeles (Los Angeles, CA) (Box 36)
  - Security Title Insurance Company (Santa Barbara, CA) (Box 36)
  - Seiber, Mátyás and Lilla, composer (Box 36)
  - Sejans, Joachim (Box 36)
  - Selznick, David O., producer (Box 36)
  - Semmelweis Scientific Society (Box 36)
  - Sendrey, Albert, composer (Box 36)
  - SESAC (New York, NY), see also Jadassohn, Kurt (Box 36)
  - Shapiro, Joseph, fan (Box 36)
  - Sheets, Walter, orchestrator (Box 36)
  - Sheirer, Sally (Box 36)
  - Shindo, Tak, musician (Box 36)
  - Shuk, Lajos, conductor (Box 36)
  - Sidney, Louis K., producer (Box 36)
  - Siegl, Henry, musician (Box 36)
  - Siegmeister, Elie, composer (Box 36)
  - Sievers, Lieselotte, see also Breitkopf & Härtel (Wiesbaden, W. Germany) (Box 36)
  - Simon & Sheridan (Los Angeles, CA), see also Sacks, Samuel (Box 36)
  - Singer, Jacques, conductor (Box 36)
  - Sklar, Jerome, accountant (Box 36)
  - Slijpen, I. (Box 36)
  - [The] Small Company (Hollywood, CA) (Box 36)
  - Smallman, Chris (Box 36)
  - Smithsonian Institution Series, Inc. (New York, NY) (Box 36)
  - Snell, Mike (Box 36)
  - Sniff's Dates and Citrus Fruits (Indio, CA) (Box 36)
  - Sobelle, Ernest (Box 36)
  - Société des Auteurs, Compositeurs et Éditerurs de Musique (Paris, France) (Box 36)
  - Society Miklós Rózsa New York (New York, NY) (Box 36)
  - Solti, Georg and Valerie, conductor (Box 37)
  - Sotheby and Co. (London, England) (Box 37)
  - Southern California Symphony Association (Los Angeles, CA) (Box 37)
  - Spivakovsky, Tossy, musician (Box 37)
  - [The] State Department (Washington, D.C.) (Box 37)
  - Staatliche Lotterie-Einnahme Freundel (Frankfurt, Germany) (Box 37)
  - Stagen Property Management, Inc. (Beverly Hills, CA) (Box 37)
  - Starker, Janos, Rae, Gwen, and Gabrielle, musician (Box 37)
  - [California] State Board of Equalization (Sacramento, CA) (Box 37)
  - Stein, Ronald, composer (Box 37)
  - Steinberg, Hans Wilhelm, conductor (Box 37)
  - Steiner, Heinrich, conductor (Box 37)
  - Steiner, Max, composer (Box 37)
  - Sternberg, Samuel, fan (Box 37)
  - Stevens, John, fan (Box 37)
  - Stevens, Leith and Peg, composer (Box 37)
  - Stewart, Norman, writer (Box 37)
  - Stichting Nederlandsche Radio-Unie (Hilversum, Netherlands) (Box 37)
  - Stiehler, Kurt, conductor (Box 37)
  - Stokowski, Leopold, conductor (Box 37)
  - Stone, Irving, writer (Box 37)
  - Stravinsky, Vera (Box 37)
  - Sturm, George (Box 37)
  - Süddeutscher Rundfunk Stuttgart (Stuttgart, Germany) (Box 37)
  - Südwest-Ton-Studio (Stuttgart, Germany), see also Jansen, Heinz (Box 37)
  - Suffredini, Philip (Box 37)
  - SUISA (Zurich, Switzerland) (Box 37)
  - Sunset Oil Company (Los Angeles, CA) (Box 37)
  - Svedrofsky, Henry, conductor (Box 37)
  - Syracuse University (Syracuse, NY) (Box 37)
  - Szabadosi, Béla (Box 37)
  - Szabo, Thomas (Box 37)
  - Szasz, Andor (Box 37)
  - Szemere, Paul Peter (Box 37)
  - Szenkar, Eugen, conductor (Box 37)
  - Szentannai, Ervinné and Adrienne (Box 37)
  - Szigeti, Joseph, musician (Box 37)
  - Szirmay, Marta, actor (Box 37)
  - Szollos, Beatrix, musician (Box 37)
  - Szücs, Istvan (Box 37)
  - T (Box 38)
  - Taht, Richard, fan (Box 38)
  - Takács, Jeno and Éva, composer (Box 38)
  - Tamkin, David N., orchestrator (Box 38)
  - Tarrant, Irving, businessman (Box 38)
  - Tátrai, Vilmos, conductor (Box 38)
  - Taylor, Alice, musician (Box 38)
  - Teale, Munro, fan (Box 38)
  - Temianka, Henri, musician (Box 38)
  - Terebesi, György, musician (Box 38)
  - Theatrical and Television Motion Picture Special Payments Fund (New York, NY) (Box 38)
  - Theodore Presser Company (Bryn Mawr, PA) (Box 38)
  - Thessaloniki International Film Festival (Thessaloniki, Greece) (Box 38)
  - Thoeren, Felix T., C. P. M., businessman (Box 38)
  - Thomas Meadows & Co., Ltd. (London, England) (Box 38)
  - Thomas, Tony, historian (Box 38)
  - Thompson, Richard, fan (Box 38)
  - Thos. Cook & Son (Rome, Italy) (Box 38)
  - Tiedtke, Larry, fan (Box 38)
  - Toch, Ernst and Lilly, composer (Box 38)
  - Toplis & Harding, Wagner & Glidden (Los Angeles, CA) (Box 38)
  - [The] Toronto Symphony Orchestra (Toronto, Ontario, Canada) (Box 38)
  - Tóth, László (Box 38)
  - Travelworld Inc. (Los Angeles, CA) (Box 38)
  - Treger, Charles, musician (Box 38)
  - Trivedi, Girish, fan (Box 38)
  - Trummeter, Georg (Box 38)
  - Tulan, Fred, musician (Box 38)
  - Turkin, Marshall (Box 38)
  - Turner, Theodore S., musician (Box 38)
  - Tusa, Erzsébet, musician; see also Lendvai, Ernö (Box 38)
  - U (Box 38)
  - Új Nyugat (New Horizons) (Chicago, IL) (Box 38)
  - Ulrichs, Andra (Box 38)
  - Ungar, Thomas, scientist (Box 38)
  - Unidentified, 3 folders (Box 38)
  - Unidentified - "Dine", family (Box 38)
  - Unidentified - "Keeri" (Box 38)
  - Unione Musicisti di Roma (Rome, Italy) (Box 38)
  - United Artists Corporation (New York, NY) (Box 38)
  - [The] United Group of Property Management Companies (Studio City, CA) (Box 38)
  - United States Army (Box 39)
  - United States Department of Health, Education and Welfare (Social Security Administration) (Box 39)
  - [The] United States Life Insurance Company (New York, NY) (Box 39)
  - United States Post Office Department (Box 39)
  - Universal Foreign Service Co. (Los Angeles, CA) (Box 39)
  - Universal Pictures Company, Inc. (Universal City, CA) (Box 39)
  - University of California, Berkeley (Berkeley, CA) (Box 39)
  - University of California, Los Angeles (Los Angeles, CA) (Box 39)
  - University of Redlands (Redlands, CA) (Box 39)
  - [The] University of Southern California (Los Angeles, CA) (Box 39)
  - [The] University of Wyoming (Laramie, WY) (Box 39)
  - Ürögdi, György (Box 39)
  - Ury, Walter and Tanya (Box 39)
  - Ustinov, Peter, writer (Box 39)
  - V (Box 39)
  - Valcauda, Armando (Box 39)
  - Valentiner, William R., historian (Box 39)
  - Valenzuela, Robert, fan (Box 39)
  - Valle Music Reproduction (North Hollywood, CA) (Box 39)
  - Vallerand, François, critic (Box 39)
  - Van Orden, Ray, fan (Box 39)
  - Van West, F.W., conservator (Box 39)
  - Vanguard Films, Inc. (Culver City, CA) (Box 39)
  - Vansittart, Lord Robert, writer (Box 39)
  - Varaday, Brian, fan (Box 39)
  - Varèse Sarabande Records, Inc. (North Hollywood, CA) (Box 39)
  - Vaughan, Clifford, musician (Box 39)
  - Veress, József (Box 40)
  - Vertlieb, Steve and Erwin, writer (Box 40)
  - Vincent, John (Box 40)
  - Vincze, Laci (Box 40)
  - Viola, Dr. György, physician (Box 40)
  - Venezia, Comune di (Box 40)
  - Vogt, C.A. (Box 40)
  - Voigt, Kai-Ingo, fan (Box 40)
  - Vox Productions, Inc. (Los Angeles, CA) (Box 40)
  - Vozárik, Roger, fan (Box 40)
  - W (Box 40)
  - WQXR (New York, NY) (Box 40)
  - Wagner, Hansjörg, artist (Box 40)
  - Wahl, Hilda (Box 40)
  - Wallraf-Richartz-Museum (Köln, Germany) (Box 40)
  - Walter, Bruno, conductor (Box 40)
  - Walter de Gruyter & Co. (Berlin, Germany) (Box 40)
  - Walton, William, composer (Box 40)
  - War Department (Washington, D.C.) (Box 40)
  - Ward, Robert, fan (Box 40)
  - Warner, Alan, producer (Box 40)
  - Warren, Elinor Remick, composer (Box 40)
  - Warren, John C., clergyperson (Box 40)
  - Washington, Eileen, musician (Box 40)
  - Waxman, Franz and Alice, composer (Box 40)
  - Waxman, John (Box 40)
  - Weber, Horst (Box 40)
  - Weissmann, János (Box 40)
  - Wescott, Steve, historian (Box 40)
  - West, John C. (Box 40)
  - Westdeutscher Rundfunk (Köln, Germany) (Box 40)
  - Westheimer, Fine, Berger & Co. (Los Angeles, CA) (Box 40)
  - Westminster Recording Co., Inc. (New York, NY) (Box 40)
  - Westwood Motors, Inc. (West Los Angeles, CA) (Box 40)
  - Wetmore, Eleanor (Box 40)
  - Whaley, Jim, fan (Box 40)
  - Wheelwright, D. Sterling, conductor (Box 40)
  - Whisenant, David, fan (Box 40)
  - Whiteside, Roberta, fan (Box 40)
  - Whittier College (Whittier, CA) (Box 41)
  - Wichita Falls Symphony Orchestra, Inc. (Wichita Falls, TX) (Box 41)
  - Wichita State University, See Bush, Martin (Box 41)
  - Wihtol, A.A., writer (Box 41)
  - Wilfrid Van Wyck Ltd. (London, England) (Box 41)
  - William Morris Agency, Inc. (Beverly Hills, CA) (Box 41)
  - Williams, John T., composer (Box 41)
  - Willits, Malcolm, fan (Box 41)
  - Willow Music (Pinner, Middlesex, England), see also Gray, Gordon (Box 41)
  - Wilson Editions (Manchester, England) (Box 41)
  - Wilson, Harry R., musician (Box 41)
  - Wolcott, Charles and Harriet, musician (Box 41)
  - Women's Athletic Club (Los Angeles, CA) (Box 41)
  - Wray, William Henry, fan (Box 41)
  - Wynwood Press (New York, NY), publisher (Box 41)
  - Y (Box 41)
  - Yacura, Michael, fan (Box 41)
  - Yamashita, Ken, fan (Box 41)
  - Yerke, Kenneth S., businessman (Box 41)
  - Yohanna, Joseph, fan (Box 41)
  - Young, David, fan (Box 41)
  - Young Musicians Foundation (Los Angeles, CA) (Box 41)
  - Z (Box 41)
  - Zador, Eugene, composer (Box 41)
  - Zephyr Oil Co. (Wilmington, CA) (Box 41)
  - Zillig, Winfried, composer (Box 41)
  - Zimbalist, Sam, producer (Box 41)
  - Zissu, Marcus, Ebenstein & Stein (New York, NY) (Box 41)
  - Zsigmondy, Dénes, musician (Box 41)
  - Zsoldos, Andor, writer (Box 41)
  - Zukerman, Pinchas, musician (Box 41)
- Fan mail
  - Letters, cards, photographs, 1940-1995; undated (Box 42)
- Compositions
  This subseries contains handwritten compositions, reproductions, and sheet music for orchestral, chamber, and choral works. Unnumbered compositions are listed first, followed by Opp. 1-45 (Op. 11 is lacking), and finally compositions by Nic Tomay, Rózsa's pseudonym.
  - By Rózsa, unnumbered
    - Camouflage, unbound handwritten composition (Oversize 1)
    - Collection: Five Songs, published sheet music; contains "My Little Town (Balassagyarmat)," "The Land Where My Heart Lies," "Invocation" Op. 16a, "Beasts of Burden" Op. 16b, and "High Flight" (Box 1)
    - Collection: Five Songs (Budapest Songs), unbound reproduction (Oversize 333)
    - Collection: Variations on Happy Birthday in Tribute to Eugene Ormandy, bound reproduction (Box 1)
    - Danse Grotesque, unbound handwritten composition (Oversize 1)
    - Dedicace, unbound handwritten composition (Oversize 2)
    - Doppio Concerto per Violino, Violoncello ed Orchestra, spiral-bound reproduction (Oversize 3)
    - Egyedul a Sengerrel, unbound handwritten composition (Oversize 4)
    - Eugene Ormandy's 70th Birthday, unbound reproduction (Oversize 5)
    - Farewell, unbound handwritten composition; "Flight" on the back (Oversize 5)
    - Festive Flourish, unbound handwritten composition (Oversize 6)
    - Festive Flourish for the Bicentennial Anniversary of the American Independence, for brass and percussion, published sheet music (Box 1)
    - Festive Flourish for the Bicentennial Anniversary of the American Independence, for brass and percussion, published sheet music (Box 1)
    - Finale (new version), unbound handwritten composition (Oversize 6)
    - Flight, unbound handwritten composition; on the back of "Farewell" (Oversize 5)
    - Fo Cenond Hercat Eloti, unbound handwritten composition (Oversize 6)
    - Fuga-Yavei, unbound handwritten composition (Oversize 6)
    - The Golden Tent, unbound handwritten composition (Oversize 6)
    - A Halal Rokona, unbound handwritten composition (Oversize 6)
    - Hauptfach Komposition, bound handwritten composition; also, reproduction photograph of Hermann Grabner and Parisi Hirlap newspaper page (Oversize 7)
    - HG, unbound handwritten composition (Oversize 8)
    - High Flight, unbound handwritten composition (Oversize 8)
    - High Flight, unbound reproduction (Oversize 333)
    - Introduction and Allegro for Viola Solo: sketches, unbound handwritten composition (Oversize 9)
    - Kis Harensong Ench, unbound handwritten composition (Oversize 9)
    - Knight Without Armour, unbound handwritten composition (Oversize 10)
    - Konsert fur Violine und Orchester, bound handwritten composition (Oversize 10)
    - Konsert fur Violine und Orchester, bound handwritten composition (Oversize 11)
    - Konsert fur Violine und Orchester, bound handwritten composition (Oversize 12)
    - Konsert fur Violine und Orchester, bound handwritten composition (Oversize 13)
    - Konsert fur Violine und Orchester (see also Op. 71), bound reproduction (Oversize 14)
    - Largo Doloroso, unbound handwritten composition (Oversize 6)
    - Lento (Tema con Variazioni, unbound handwritten composition (Oversize 15)
    - Love Song from The Thief of Baghdad, unbound handwritten composition (Oversize 15)
    - Love Theme from Ben Hur, unbound handwritten composition (Oversize 15)
    - Lydia, unbound handwritten composition (Oversize 15)
    - Lygia: "Nostalgia", unbound handwritten composition (Oversize 15)
    - The Magnifying Glass, unbound handwritten composition (Oversize 15)
    - Markovadolin Ballet, bound reproduction with Rózsa's markings (Oversize 16)
    - The Miracle (New), unbound handwritten composition (Oversize 16)
    - Motette fur 2 Chore a capella, unbound handwritten composition (Oversize 17)
    - Quartetto per Archi No. 2, unbound handwritten composition and reproductions (Oversize 89)
    - Quintett fur Pianoforte, Two Violines, und Violoncello, unbound handwritten composition (Oversize 90)
    - Reminiscences of the Puszta (Puszrai emlék), unbound reproduction (Box 4)
    - Scherzo, unbound handwritten composition (Oversize 90)
    - Scherzi fur Kammerorchester (unpublished), bound reproduction (Oversize 91)
    - Sextett, unbound handwritten composition (Oversize 92)
    - Sonata, unbound handwritten composition (Oversize 93)
    - Sonata for Violin and Piano, unbound handwritten composition (Oversize 94)
    - Sonate, unbound reproduction (Oversize 95)
    - Sonatina, unbound handwritten composition (Oversize 96)
    - Spy in Black (Title Music), unbound handwritten composition (Oversize 98)
    - Sonatine fur Klavier in E moll, unbound handwritten composition and reproductions (Oversize 97)
    - Sunward I've Climbed: baritone and piano (unpublished), unbound handwritten composition (Oversize 98)